Guide to the Office of Multicultural Affairs Records 1987-2004
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Office of Multicultural Affairs Records
1987-2004
1991-2004
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
RG 225
Oregon State University. Office of Multicultural Affairs.
12.1 cubic feet, including 78 photographs 14 boxes and 1 map folder
The Office of Multicultural Affairs Records document the administration and functioning of the Office, which was established in 1991, and the variety of multicultural programs and activities for students and faculty at Oregon State University. The Records also reflect the many associated duties of Phyllis Lee, Director of the Office of Multicultural Affairs from 1992 until her retirement in 2003.
Historical Note:
Formed in 1991, the Office of Multicultural Affairs assists OSU in the promotion of cultural diversity, awareness, and sensitivity throughout the campus community. In this capacity, the office serves as a resource for the OSU community and the region in understanding multicultural issues; helps in the recruitment and retention of students, staff, and faculty from ethnic, racial, and other underrepresented groups; participates in curriculum development; and provides consultation services to all academic and support units.
The development of the Office of Multicultural Affairs is rooted in recommendations made by two advisory bodies, the OSU Board of Visitors and the Minority Affairs Commission. Created by President Byrne in 1986 to investigate ways to enhance diversity at OSU, the Board of Visitors advocated for the formation of a Minority Affairs Commission, which, in turn, argued for the establishment of an office devoted to addressing multicultural affairs. Phyllis Lee became the office’s first director.
After Lee retired in 2003, the Office of Multicultural Affairs was renamed the Office of Community and Diversity and Terryl Ross appointed as new director in 2004. The basic mission of the office, however, did not change.
Appointed to the OSU Board of Visitors in 1986, Phyllis Lee served as acting director of the Office of Multicultural Affairs before assuming the directorship in 1992. After earning a doctorate in counseling from OSU in 1983, Lee worked for Kaiser Permanente in Portland before returning to campus in 1991. Lee also worked as a public school teacher and in counseling education at Portland State University prior to her post with the Office of Multicultural Affairs.
The Office of Multicultural Affairs Records document the establishment of the office in 1991 and its administration and programs under the first director, Phyllis Lee. The Records represent the many issues pertaining to ethnicity, gender, and multiculturism at Oregon State University in the 1990s and early 2000s as well as the extensive activities, both on- and off-campus, of Phyllis Lee.
Organized into 15 series: I. Correspondence; II. Committees; III. Staff Meetings; IV. Reports; V. Curriculum Development and Instruction; VI. Scholarships; VII. Presentations; VIII. Newspaper Clippings; IX. Notes; X. Subject Files; XI. Publications; XII. Student Papers; XIII. Off-Campus Organizations and Committees; XIV. Harassment Incident Files; and XV. Photographs.
Collection is open for research with the exception of the Harrassment Incident Files (Series XIV). Access to this series is restricted and subject to review by the reference archivist.
Records transferred from the Office of Community and Diversity in 2005.
Additions to the collection are expected.
Documentation pertaining to the Office of Multicultural Affairs is represented elsewhere in the holdings of the OSU Archives. Interaction between the office and the university president and student government can be found in the records of the President’s Office (RG 13) and the Associated Students of OSU (RG 11).
The Oregon Multicultural Archives documents the lives and activities of African American, Asian American, Latino and Native American communities of Oregon. Records from other departments at OSU involved with issues of ethnic and racial diversity are also held by the Archives: the Diversity Development Office (RG 228), the Educational Opportunities Program (RG 230), and the Minority Education Office (RG 229).
Lee, Phyllis S.
American Association of University Administrators.; Associated Students of Oregon State University.; Educational Opportunities Program (Oregon State University); National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges.; Oregon State University--Administration.; Oregon State University--Faculty.; Oregon State University--Students.; Oregon State University. Dept. of Ethnic Studies.; Oregon State University. Minority Education Office.; Oregon State University. Office of the President.; Oregon State University. President's Commission on the Status of Women.; Oregon University System.; Oregon State System of Higher Education.; Urban League of Portland (Portland, Or.)
College environment--Oregon--Corvallis.; Diversity in the workplace--Oregon--Corvallis.; Gay college students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Minority college students--Oregon.; Minorities--Oregon.; Multicultural education--Oregon.; Multiculturalism--Oregon.; Student activities--Oregon--Corvallis.
Corvallis (Or.)--Race relations.
Photographs.
African Americans; Civil Rights; Colleges and Universities; Gays and Lesbians; Latinos and Latinas; Native Americans; Student Life; Women; Oregon; Corvallis; Portland; Photographs
- Correspondence, 1989-2004; Series I
  Primarily made up of correspondence, Series I also contains newspaper clippings, notes, publications, and reports. This series documents interaction between Phyllis Lee and OSU administrative units, academic departments, campus cultural centers, Corvallis city government, and regional ethnic and racial advocacy organizations such the Urban League of Portland. Topics reflected in this series include requests for Lee’s intervention as a consultant and mediator, campus diversity initiatives, support for student participation in off-campus conferences, accreditation, presentations by visiting scholars and activists on subjects of racism and culture, outreach projects to minority communities, an assessment survey on campus climate, minority action plans from various OSU departments and colleges, and the Office of Multicultural Affairs’ coordination of conferences and events highlighting student diversity.
  - Accreditation, 1994-2001 (Box 1)
  - Admissions and Orientation Office, 1994-2003 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1991-2004 (Box 1)
  - Associated Students of OSU (ASOSU), 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Awards Received by Phyllis Lee, 1994-2001 (Box 1)
  - Barometer Newspaper, 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - Brochure and Resource Guide Development, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Campus Climate Assessment Survey, 2002-2004; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Community Outreach, 1996-2004
    - African-American Events, 1997-2004 (Box 1)
    - Asian/Pacific American Events, 1997-2004; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - General, 1998-2002; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Latino Events, 1996-2002; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Native American Events, 1999-2004 (Box 1)
  - Community Relations Project, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
  - Corvallis City Government, 1992-2003 (Box 1)
  - Corvallis Police Department, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Dean’s Council Meeting with Students of Color, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Development Office-Proposals for Minority Oriented Projects, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program, 1996-2003 (Box 1)
  - Distance Education Programs, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Diversity Action Plan Development, 1995-2004 (Box 1)
  - Diversity Hiring Initiatives, 1998-2004 (Box 2)
  - Diversity Training Center at OSU, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Education, School of, 1992-2001 (Box 2)
  - Educational Opportunities Program, 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Engineering, College of, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Event Planning, 1992-2003
    - Asian/Pacific American Celebrations, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
    - Bone Marrow Donor Registration Drive, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
    - Campus Together Day, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Enhancing Race Relations on Campus Conference, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Halsell Hall Dedication, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Kaleidoscope of Colleges and Cultures Open House Events, 1994-2002 (Box 2)
    - La Raza Room Dedication, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Oregon Trail Celebration “York” Presentation, 1993 (Box 2)
    - OSU International Year of the Family Conference, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Pacific Northwest Chicano Conference, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Sacred Landscapes Conference, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Facilities Services, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Senate: Proposal for a Diversity Council, 1999-2004 (Box 2)
  - Fraternities and Sororities, 1994-1999 (Box 2)
  - General, 1990-2003 (Box 2)
  - Hewlett-Packard Diversity Initiative, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Hispanic Migrant Community and OSU, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Holiday Observance Policies, 1991-2001 (Box 2)
  - Human Resources Dept.-Staff Development Coordinator, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Indian Education Office, 1990-2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Institutional Research and Planning Unit-Budgets and Planning Office, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
  - InterACTION Project/Kellogg Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
  - International Students, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Jumpstart Program (Coca Cola Foundation/Art Department), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Leadership and Educational Experiences in Ag. and Diversity (LEEAD), 1998 (Box 2)
  - Liberal Arts, College of, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Logo Development, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Media Outreach, 1991-2001 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Union Program Council, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Mentoring Programs, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Minority Actions Plans from Various OSU Colleges, 1989-1996 (Box 2)
  - Minority Education Offices, 1993-1999 (Box 2)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) Corvallis Branch, 1993-2004 (Box 2)
  - Native American Roundtable Meetings, 2003 (Box 2)
  - New Student Programs Office, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
  - Non-Discrimination and Harassment Policies, 1990-1998 (Box 2)
  - Northwest Regional China Council, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Office of Multicultural Affairs, 1991-2003
    - Budgets, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
    - Distribution of Funds to Diversity Oriented Events and Programs, 1996-2003 (Box 2)
    - Establishment of the Office, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Program Descriptions and Mission Statements, 1992-2003 (Box 2)
    - Strategic Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Ombudsperson/Mediation Team Proposal, 1991-2002 (Box 2)
  - OSU Cultural Centers, 1992-2002
    - Coordinator Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - General, 1992-2002 (Box 2)
    - Meetings with President Byrne, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - Native American Longhouse, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - OSU Extension Service, 1999-2002 (Box 3)
  - OSU Library, 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - OSU President’s Office, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
  - OSU 2007 Roundtable Forums, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Oregon Student Lobby, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Pharmacy, College of, 1994-1997 (Box 3)
  - Photo Directory of OSU Students/Staff Proposal, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Presentations by Visiting Scholars and Activists, 1992-2003
    - Dula, Annette, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Elliott, Jane, 2003; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Frohnmayer, John, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
    - Holloway, Karla, 1995 (Box 3)
    - McCunn, Ruthanne Lum (two events), 1995-2000 (Box 3)
    - McIntosh, Peggy, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
    - McLaurin, Sylvia, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Rodriquez, Eloy, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Sermol, Dorothy (multicultural consultant), 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Vachss, Alice, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Wassmuth, Bill, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Wise, Tim, 2001; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Zia, Helen, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Queer Education Office, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Racial/Ethnicity Identity Classification Codes, 1992-1995 (Box 3)
  - Requests for Consultation and Review, 1992-1998 (Box 3)
  - Reviews of Campus Diversity Initiatives, 1996-2002 (Box 3)
  - Roper, Larry, 1996-1998 (Box 3)
  - Roy Arnold-OSU Provost and Executive Vice President (meetings), 1991-1999; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - September 11 NYC Terrorist Attack-University Response, 2001; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Student Affairs Office, 1993-1998 (Box 3)
  - Student Athletes, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Student Attendance of Conferences and Workshops, 1992-1998 (Box 3)
  - Student Boycott in Response to Racial Incident, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Timeline of Programs Promoting Cultural Diversity, 1994 (Box 3)
  - University Advancement Office, 2000 (Box 3)
  - University Publications Office, 1997-2001 (Box 3)
  - University Strategic Planning Aims, 1995-2003 (Box 3)
  - University Vision and Cultural Diversity Statements, 1992-1998 (Box 3)
  - Urban League of Portland, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Various On-Campus Workshops and Meetings, 1992-2001 (Box 3)
  - Visits to Campus by Non-OSU Faculty and Activists, 1994-2000 (Box 3)
  - Visits and Tours by Prospective Students, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
- Committees, 1989-2004; Series II
  Series II consists of materials generated by various university committees, commissions, and advisory boards and is made up of meeting minutes, correspondence, notes, reports, and publications. Topics reflected in this series include hate-related activities on campus, the recruitment and retention of students and color, gender equity in the NCAA, the OSU 2007 strategic planning process, cross cultural outreach, diversity in course development, and response strategies to racial incidents.
  - Academic Council (OUS), 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Advancement of Teaching Committee, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Affirming Diversity Course Development Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Asian Cultural Center Advisory Board, 1998-2002 (Box 4)
  - Asian/Pacific American Education Office Advisory Board, 1998-2001 (Box 4)
  - Asian Pacific American Student Union, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Association of Faculty for the Advancement of People of Color, 1999-2004 (Box 4)
  - Brown vs. Board of Education Commemoration Group, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Character and Community Task Force, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - Coalition for Cross Cultural Outreach, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Commission on Racism, 1990-1992; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Committee on Committees, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Community Relation Project Group, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program Advisory Board, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Diversity Programs Workgroup, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Diversity 2000 Planning Committee, 1997-1999; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Enrollment Workgroup, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Ethical Development Committee, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Awards Committee, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Mediation Committee, 2000-2002 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Senate Executive Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Foods Systems Professions Education Steering Committee(InterACTION Project), 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Gender Equity and Minority Task Force (Athletics), 2001 (Box 4)
  - Kaleidoscope of Colleges and Cultures-Planning Core Committee, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
  - Marketing Strategic Advisory Committee, 1997 (Box 4)
  - May 30th Diversity Group, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - Minority Affairs Commission, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - NCAA Equity Committee, 2000; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Office of Multicultural Affairs 2000 Committee, 1998 (Box 5)
  - OSU Board of Advisors, 2002 (Box 5)
  - OSU Honorary Doctorate Committee, 1997-2000 (Box 5)
  - OSU Institutional Review Board - Human Subjects Committee, 1996-2002 (Box 5)
  - OSU 2007 Community and Student Development Subgroup, 2002 (Box 5)
  - OSU 2007 Curricular Issues Planning Team Satellite Group 2-Faculty Issues, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - OSU 2007 Diversity Redesign Committee-Students with Disabilities Focus Group, 2002 (Box 5)
  - OSU 2007 Student Experience Diversity Subgroup, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - OSU 2007 Student Services Redesign Group, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - President’s Cabinet, 1993-1995 (Box 5)
  - President’s Commission on Campus Climate, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - President’s Commission on Hate-Related Activities, 1994-1998; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - President’s Commission on the Status of Women, 1991-2004
    - 1991-1995, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 6)
  - Pride Celebration 2004 Steering Committee (Box 6)
  - Professional and Managerial Internships in State Employment (PROMISE) Task Force, 1993-2004; 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Provost’s Council, 1993-2003; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Recruitment Work Group, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
  - Salary Equity Planning Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - September 11 Commemoration Committee, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Sexual Assault Task Force, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - STAART-2 (Student Affairs Administrative Response Team) (racial incident response policies), 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Student Affairs Campus Compact Diversity Initiative Committee, 1997-1999 (Box 6)
  - Student Athlete Advisory Board, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Students of Color Recruitment and Retention Committee, 1998-2003; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - TEAM (Together Everyone Accomplishes More) Task Force, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Transitions Planning Groups, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Council Diversity Workgroup, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Education Council, 1998-2001 (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Education Council-Retention Workgroup, 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - University Council, 1994 (Box 7)
  - University Publications Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - University Scholarship Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 7)
  - Vice Provost for Research Advisory Board, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Weatherford International Residential College Academic Program Group, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Web Translations Steering Committee, 1997 (Box 7)
- Staff Meetings, 1993-1996; Series III (Box 7)
  Series III documents Office of Multicultural Affairs staff meetings and is primarily made up of notes, but also includes correspondence, meeting agendas, and flyers.
- Reports, 1987-2004; Series IV
  In addition to annual summaries of Office of Multicultural Affairs' and Phyllis Lee's activities, the reports in Series IV include status reports on ethnic and racial diversity at OSU and the Oregon University System, OSU strategic planning documents, harassment response guidelines, updates on diversity initiatives at OSU, and a survey study on campus climate in Oregon.
  - Annual Reports, 1992-1998; 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Annual Reports-Notes for, 1998-2004 (Box 7)
  - Campus Climate Survey: Conducted for the Oregon State System of Higher Education (OSSHE) (survey report), 1997 (Box 7)
  - Challenging Times, Clear Choices: An Action Agenda for College Access and Success (National Dialogue on Student Financial Aid), 2003 (Box 7)
  - Diversity at OSU 1998-1999: Reports from the Campus (Box 7)
  - Diversity Initiatives at OSU-Status Report and Update, 1999-2003 (Box 7)
  - Diversity 2000: Working Together a 21st Century Guide, 1999 (Box 7)
  - External Review of Student and Faculty Racial/Ethnic Diversity Initiatives (OSSHE), 1996 (Box 7)
  - Implementation of the Enrollment Management Review Team Recommendations, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Minority Action Program, 1989 (Box 7)
  - NCAA (National Collegiate Athletic Association) Certification Self-Study Report, 2000 (Box 7)
  - A New Breed of Beaver-Integrating Ethnic Studies and International Education, undated (Box 7)
  - New Faculty Diversity Initiatives in OSSHE, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Office of Multicultural Affairs Administrative Cost/Structure Assessment, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Office of Multicultural Affairs Status Report, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Oregon Action Plan for Diversifying the Education Workforce, 1998 (Box 7)
  - OSU Response to Discriminatory Harassment Incidents, 2002 (Box 7)
  - OSU Shaping the Future: 5-Year Strategic Plan (draft), 2003 (Box 8)
  - OSU in the 21st Century: Budget and Redesign Teams Report, 2001 (Box 8)
  - OSU 2007: Enhancing and Sustaining Local and Global Communities, Environments, and Economies, undated (Box 8)
  - Oregon University System Diversity Report: The Benefits of Diversity on Campus and Beyond, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Oregon University System Diversity Report: National Trends, and Racial/Ethnic Diversity among OUS Students, Instructional Faculty, and Staff, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Oregon University System Diversity Report: Student, Faculty, and Staff Racial/Ethnic Diversity-A Retrospective of Five and Ten-Year Progress, 2003 (Box 8)
  - President’s Reports on the State of Racial/Ethnic Diversity, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Professional Faculty Issues Group Report, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Racism at OSU: Findings of the President’s Commission on Racism, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Report to the OSU Student Affairs Dept. Heads frm the Diversity Programs Work Group, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Status of Ethnic and Racial Diversity: OSU, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Status of Minority Faculty Recruitment and Retention and Perceptions of the Campus Climate by Minority Faculty, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Study of Racial and Ethnic Relations in Portland (City Club of Portland), 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Undergraduate Admissions Criteria Issue Group Preliminary Report, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Working Together for the Future Towards Racial and Cultural Diversity at OSU, (Board of Visitors for Minority Affairs), 1987 (Box 8)
- Curriculum Development and Instruction, 1991-2004; Series V
  Series V documents Phyllis Lee’s participation in classroom instruction and proposals for the development of new academic programs and departments. This series contains correspondence, grant proposals, handouts, presentation notes, publications, and syllabi.
  - Participation in Classes, 1996-2004
    - ALS 199 (Ethics, Culture and Influence: The Role of Media in America), 2001 (Box 8)
    - COMM (Media Subjects), 2000 (Box 8)
    - CSSA (College Student Services Admin.) Courses, 1997-2001 (Box 8)
    - ED 201 (Education Seminar Series), 2004 (Box 8)
    - ELI (English Language Institute) Culture Class, 1997 (Box 8)
    - H 434 (Health Care Law and Regulation), 1999 (Box 8)
    - H 537 (Management of Human Resources in Healthcare Orgs), 1997 (Box 8)
    - Linguistics 251 (Languages of Oregon), 2004 (Box 8)
    - LS 406 (Student Media Project), 2003 (Box 8)
    - LS 406 (Writing Grant Proposals), 1998 (Box 8)
    - Multicultural Health, 2004 (Box 8)
    - OSU Odyssey Courses, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
    - Social, Cultural, and Political Foundations of Education, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Women’s Studies 399, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Program Proposals, 1991-2001
    - CAMP (College Assistant Migrant Program) Grant Proposal, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Ethnic Studies Department Proposal for Establishment, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Minority Scholars Network, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
    - Multicultural Scholars Program for Home Economics, 1994-1997 (Box 8)
    - Safe Haven Program for Survivors of Violence, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Wetland Exploration Team Project, 2000 (Box 8)
- Scholarships, 1991-2002; Series VI
  Series VI documents scholarship programs for ethnic and racial minorities offered by OSU, the Oregon University System, and private institutions. In addition to correspondence, there are also blank applications, flyers, meeting minutes, notes, reports, and statistical data in this series.
  - Chinese American Citizens Alliance Scholarship, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Diversity Achievement Scholarship Program, 2001-2002; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - General, 1993-2001 (Box 8)
  - Junior Year Minority Achievement Scholarship (JMAS) Program, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
  - Oregonian Publishing Company Scholarship Fund Advisory Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Proctor and Gamble Ethnic/Racial Diversity Minority Student Scholarship, 1992-1998 (Box 8)
  - Safeco Ethnic/Racial Diversity Minority Student Scholarship, 1993-1998 (Box 8)
  - Under-Represented Minority Achievement Scholarship Program, 1990-1998; 2 folders (Box 8)
- Presentations, 1991-2004; Series VII